Yury Voloshin

186 Bay 26th St., Apt 3A, Brooklyn, NY 11214 (917) 349-8135 yvoloshino1@gmail.com

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

My background blends 3+ years of software development experience using PHP/Symfony/Vue.js with the problem-solving and analytical mindset developed as a Ph.D.-level chemical engineer to offer solid skills in web application building, as well as systematic testing and debugging approaches.

Languages: PHP, MySQL, Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Tools: Symfony, Linux, jQuery, Twitter Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, Git, Bitbucket, GitHub, Heroku

Portfolio page and blog: yvoloshin.github.io

EXPERIENCE

Columbia University, New York, NY Associate Software Developer

7/2017 - present

- Used Symfony and Vue.js to develop online tools for administrators of Columbia University using using a test-driven approach and RESTful architectures both on an individual basis and as part of an Agile team of developers
- Used Codeception and PhantomJS to create acceptance and integration tests
- Wrote MySQL queries
- Contributed to product design for new applications
- Interacted with clients to discuss project specifications
- Technologies: Linux/Apache/MySQL/PHP stack, Symfony framework, Vue.js, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Git, Bitbucket, HTML/CSS, Codeception, PhantomJS, Elasticsearch

Columbia University, New York, NY Junior Software Developer

1/2016 - 7/2017

- Developed front-end and back-end aspects of online tools for administrators of Columbia University using using a test-driven approach and RESTful architectures both on an individual basis and as part of an Agile team of developers
- Used Codeception to create acceptance and integration tests
- Technologies: Linux/Apache/MySQL/PHP stack, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Git, Bitbucket, HTML/CSS

The Firehose Project Web Development School, Boston, MA (remote position)Support Engineer 10/2015 – present

• Reviewed and troubleshot students' web development projects (Ruby on Rails)

BASF Catalysts Inc., Iselin, NJ Research Engineer

7/2008 - 7/2014

- Developed software for calculating pressure drop across catalytic converters using C#
- Created mathematical models of automotive catalytic converters

Yury Voloshin – Page Two (917) 349-8135 | yvoloshino1@gmail.com

Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJ

Ph. D. Candidate / Graduate Research Assistant

5/2004 - 5/2008

- Developed a novel lab-scale process for production of hydrogen peroxide
- Created a mathematical model of the hydrogen peroxide process
- Award: Robert C. Stanley Graduate Fellowship in Engineering and Science

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Web Development, Algorithm, and Data Structures Foundations - Firehose Project (5/2015 – 8/2015)

- Learned how to build-out basic CRUD Rails apps following standard Rails conventions (without using scaffolding), involving mailers, validations, image uploading on AWS S3 and nested RESTful routes
- Implemented tests using the MiniTest's Test::Unit syntax for both unit and functional tests
- Worked through traditional computer science algorithms and data structures challenges
- Pair programmed with senior web developers as well as with peers

MyRecipeBox https://allmyrecipes.herokuapp.com Personal Project Application for storing and displaying recipes (Ruby on Rails, Postgresql, Heroku, Sass)

• Conceptualized and wireframed the app

RoutineTrack http://www.routinetrack.com Personal Project Ongoing Application for creating and tracking workout routines (Ruby on Rails, Postgresql, Heroku, Sass, jQuery)

- Conceptualized and wireframed the app
- Developed a system for creating and tracking workout routines

EDUCATION

Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJ Ph.D. in Chemical Engineering Bachelor of Engineering in Chemical Engineering

New York University, New York, NY **Bachelor of Science in Chemistry**

Foreign Languages: Russian (fluent)

Other Activities: author of a cookbook (<u>mvBook.to/cookbook</u>)